

Research Scientis

1001 6th Ave 5th floor, New York, NY 10018

I am a Research Scientist at Facebook Research. Previously, I worked on neural interfaces at CTRL-labs. Prior to that, I did my thesis at Stanford with Vijay Pande on statistical modeling and representation learning of complex biomolecular dynamics.

Experience	
Facebook Research Research Scientist	New York, NY, USA 2019 - PRESENT
CTRL-labs Research Scientist	New York, NY, USA 2018 - 2019
Stanford University NSF Graduate Research Fellow w/ Vijay S. Pande	Stanford, CA, USA 2013 - 2018
Education	
Stanford University Ph.D. in Biophysics	Stanford, CA, USA 2013 - 2018
Thesis: "Towards a Deeper Understanding of Molecular Mechanics"	
Columbia University in the City of New York  B.S. in Applied Mathematics	New York, NY, USA 2009 - 2013
Publications	
Kinetic Machine Learning Unravels Ligand-Directed Conformational Change of $\mu$ -Opioid Receptor EN Feinberg, AB Farimani, CX Hernández, and VS Pande bioRxiv (doi: 10.1101/170886)	2018
Variational Encoding of Complex Dynamics CX Hernández*, HK Wayment-Steele*, MM Sultan*, BE Husic, and VS Pande Phys. Rev. E (doi: 10.1103/PhysRevE.97.062412)	2018
Using Deep Learning for Segmentation, and Counting within Microscopy Data CX Hernández, MM Sultan, and VS Pande arXiv (arXiv: 1802.10548)	2018
Markov State Models Provide Insights into Dynamic Modulation of Protein Function  D Shukla, CX Hernández, JK Weber, and VS Pande  Accounts of Chemical Research (doi: 10.1021/ar5002999)	2015
Structure-based Network Analysis of An Evolved G-Protein Coupled Receptor Homodimer Interface SE Nichols*, CX Hernández*, Y Wang, and JA McCammon Protein Science (doi: 10.1002/pro.2258)	2013
Understanding the Origins of a Pandemic Virus CX Hernández, J Chan, H Khiabanian, and R Rabadan arXiv (arXiv: 1104.4568)	2011

MolEncoder: Molecular Autoencoder in PyTorch 2017 CX Hernández GitHub (url: https://github.com/cxhernandez/molencoder) ● Python ★ 56 \$ 10 MDEntropy: Information-Theoretic Analyses for Molecular Dynamics 2017 CX Hernández and VS Pande The Journal of Open Source Software (doi: 10.21105/joss.00427) ● Python ★ 19 ₽8 MSMExplorer: Data Visualizations for Biomolecular Dynamics 2017 CX Hernández, MP Harrigan, MM Sultan, and VS Pande The Journal of Open Source Software (doi: 10.21105/joss.00188) ● Python ★ 12 1/2 13 MSMBuilder: Statistical Models for Biomolecular Dynamics 2017 MP Harrigan, MM Sultan, CX Hernández, BE Husic, P Eastman, CR Schwantes, KA Beauchamp, RT McGibbon, and VS Pande Biophysical Journal (doi: 10.1016/j.bpj.2016.10.042) ● Python ★ 95 \$269 Osprey: Hyperparameter Optimization for Machine Learning 2016 RT McGibbon, CX Hernández, MP Harrigan, S Kearnes, MM Sultan, S Jastrzebski, BE Husic, and VS The Journal of Open Source Software (doi: 10.21105/joss.00034) Python **★** 71 \$\mathbb{P} 22 MDTraj: A Modern, Open Library for the Analysis of Molecular Dynamics 2015 **Trajectories** RT McGibbon, KA Beauchamp, MP Harrigan, C Klein, JM Swails, CX Hernández, CR Schwantes, LP Wang, TJ Lane, and VS Pande Biophysical Journal (doi: 10.1016/j.bpj.2015.08.015) ■ Python ★ 253 \$ 163 Posters & Presentations \_\_\_ Convolutional Neural Networks for Visual Recognition (CS231N) Stanford, CA, USA **Invited Presentation** 2017 "Using Deep Learning for Segmentation and Counting within Microscopy Data" **Biophysical Society Meeting** Los Angeles, CA, USA 2016 "Intrinsic Disorder in the P53 C-Terminal Regulatory Domain Yields Multiple Pathways for Folding-Upon-Binding" Workshop on Molecular and Chemical Kinetics Berlin, DEU 2015 "Inferring Causality Along Transition State Pathways" Honors & Awards

- 2013 ADVANCE Summer Research Fellowship, Stanford University
- 2013 Graduate Research Fellowship, National Science Foundation
- 2012 EXROP Undergraduate Research Fellowship, Howard Hughes Medical Institute
- 2011 Genentech Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship, Columbia University Genentech

## Press\_

- 2012 Pandemic Flu Risk Raised by Lax Hog-Farm Surveillance, Wired Magazine
- 2011 The Origin and Evolution of a Pandemic Virus, MAGNet Newsletter